Oliver Tambo Papers 2000.0144
Archives & Special Collections at the Thomas J. Dodd Research Center, University of Connecticut Libraries
- Series C: Special Topics
  - Countries (Box C2)
    - Portugal (Box C2., Folder 56)
      - General, Pamphlet--" Portugal’s Democratic Coup," Special Supplement to Resister, Third Quarter, 1990 (Box C2., Folder 56.2)
    - Romania (Box C2., Folder 57)
      - Oliver Tambo Correspondence (7 items), 1973, 1986, 1988 (Box C2., Folder 57.1)
        Correspondents include Nicolae Ceausescu. Subjects include Assistance provided by the Romanian Communist Party to the ANC; Visit to Romania.
    - Sahrawi Arab Democratic Republic (Box C2., Folder 58)
      - Oliver Tambo Correspondence (7 items), 1986-1990 (Box C2., Folder 58.1)
        Correspondents include Mohamed Abdelaziz (President). Subjects include 10th Anniversary of the Sahrawi Arab Democratic Republic; Celebrations of "the launching of the armed struggle against Spanish colonialism and Moroccan expansionism" (May 20, 1987); Release of Nelson Mandela and the unbanning of the ANC.
    - Saudi Arabia (Box C2., Folder 59)
      - Oliver Tambo Correspondence (3 items), 1973, 1986 (Box C2., Folder 59.1)
        Correspondent King Faisal; Subjects include invitation extended to Oliver Tambo on the occasion of the National Day; Oil Embargo directed against the State of Israel.
      - General (Box C2., Folder 59.2)
        - Correspondence (2 items), 1987, 1989 (Box C2., Folder 59.2.1)
    - Senegal (Box C2., Folder 60)
      - Oliver Tambo Correspondence (4 items), 1989-1990 (Box C2., Folder 60.1)
        Correspondents include Abdou Diouf. Subjects include 29th Anniversary of Independence of Senegal; Release of Nelson Mandela.
    - Somalia (Box C2., Folder 61)
      - Oliver Tambo Correspondence (2 items), circa 1963, 1984 (Box C2., Folder 61.1)
        Correspondents include Adam Mohamed Ali; Abdullah Issa. Subjects include Arrest of Nelson Mandela; Socialist Inter-African General Council, 1984 June.
    - South Africa (Box C2., Folder 62)
      - Oliver Tambo Correspondence (7 items), 1987-1991 (Box C2., Folder 62.1)
        Correspondents include PFP/DP; South African Communist Party ( SACP); Pik Botha. Subjects include South African political crisis (article by Colin Eglin in the Sunday Times, 1986); 7th Congress of the SACP; Five Freedoms Forum conference in Lusaka.
    - 'Independent States' within South Africa's Borders and Homelands (Box C2., Folder 63)
      - Bophuthatswana (Box C2., Folder 63.1)
        - Reports-- Various ANC reports (21 items), 1983-1984 (Box C2., Folder 63.1.1)
        - Press Release re Attacks on residents of Braklaagte. (Issued by Western Transvaal Region), 1991 April 11 (Box C2., Folder 63.1.2)
      - Kangwane (Box C2., Folder 63.2)
        - Address--"Address to SA British Trade Association" by Chief Minister Enos J. Mabuza of Kangwane and President of Inyandza National Movement (Box C2., Folder 63.2.1)
        - Documents--4th Kangwane Legislative Assembly (Box C2., Folder 63.2.2)
      - Lebowa (Box C2., Folder 63.3)
        - Speeches--Transcripts of 4 speeches made by M. N. Ramodike ( Lebowa People's Party) entitled "Political Stance of M. N. Ramodike", Lusaka, 1989 September 12 (Box C2., Folder 63.3.1)
      - Transkei (Box C2., Folder 63.4)
        - Address--Major Geneneral Bantu Holomisa. "South African Negotiations, One Person/One Vote and Implications for the Future," (21st African-American Institute Conference, Cairo), 1991 January 7 - 10 (Box C2., Folder 63.4.1)
        - A State in the Making - Progress in the Transkei, Issued by the Department of Information/Government Printer Cape Town, 1970 (Box C2., Folder 63.4.2)
        - "Aspects of the Non-Agricultural Economy in the Transkei" (Box C2., Folder 63.4.3)
    - Spain (Box C2., Folder 64)
      - Oliver Tambo Correspondence (2 items), 1991 (Box C2., Folder 64.1)
        Correspondence with Felipe Gonzales.
    - Sudan (Box C2., Folder 65)
      - Oliver Tambo Correspondence (4 items), 1983 (Box C2., Folder 65.1)
        Correspondents include K. M. El-Mekki; Badr Eldin Suliman (Secretary of the Central Leadership/ Sudanese Socialist Union). Subjects include Socialist Inter-African Meeting, Khartoum, 1983.
      - General-- Sudan Review published by the Central Committee of the Sudanese Communist Party (Box C2., Folder 65.2)
    - Swaziland (Box C2., Folder 66)
      - Oliver Tambo Correspondence (4 items), undated, 1984, 1990 (Box C2., Folder 66.1)
        Correspondents E. B. B. Gamedze (High Commissioner); King Mswati III. Subjects include 75th Anniversary of the ANC; Release of Nelson Mandela and unbanning of ANC.
      - General (Box C2., Folder 66.2)
        - Correspondence (3 items) (Box C2., Folder 66.2.1)
          Correspondents Jacob Zuma; B. S. S. Mabizela. Subjects Swaziland's reaction to 23 ANC cadres with military training going to ground; detention of an ANC member; parcel bomb - Bafana Duma/ambushing of ANC truck.
        - Memorandum presented by the National Executive Committee to the Government of Swaziland on the agreement between Swaziland and the Pretoria Regime on Ka-Ngwane, and Ngwavuma, 1982 July 15 (Box C2., Folder 66.2.2)
        - Communiqué - talks between Executive Secretary of the OAU Liberation Committee and a Swaziland delegation of Ministers and Officials re problems with the ANC, 1985 March 8 (Box C2., Folder 66.2.3)
        - Miscellaneous item re Conference in Swaziland, 1985 (Box C2., Folder 66.2.4)
    - Sweden (Box C2., Folder 67)
      - Oliver Tambo Correspondence (12 items), undated, 1977-1991 (Box C2., Folder 67.1)
        Correspondents include Ingvar Carlsson; Lisbet and Olaf Palme; Carl J. Persson (Ambassador); Swedish Communist Party; Swedish Liberal Party. Subjects include National Convention of the Swedish Liberal Party (1977); International Seminar on Southern Africa organised by the AIC ( International Centre of the Swedish Labour Movement), 1983; Swedish government decision to licence all trade with South Africa; Message of condolences on the death of Bernt Carlsson; Inauguration ceremony of new Swedish Embassy, Lusaka; Release of Nelson Mandela and the unbanning of the ANC; 79th Anniversary of the ANC.
      - General (Box C2., Folder 67.2)
        - Correspondence (1 item) (Box C2., Folder 67.2.1)
          Telex - Olaf Palme (thanking T T Nkobi for the message of sympathy received on behalf of the ANC on the death of King Adolf Gustaf VI, 1973 November 7.
        - Agendas (2 items) (Box C2., Folder 67.2.2)
          - Visit of Oliver Tambo, Mr. Kunene and Mr. Legaffick, Stockholm, 1973 January 7 - 10
          - Congress of the Socialist International, Stockholm, 1989 June 20 - 22
        - Papers, Speeches and Messages (5 items) (Box C2., Folder 67.2.3)
          - Peace Now - Swedish Youth Rally: Sibusiso Bengu
          - Tribute to Olaf Palme by the Swedish Minister of Health and Social Affairs, Gertrude Sigurdsen, 1986 March
          - Booklet: Speech made at the "Swedish People's Parliament against Apartheid" on 21 February 1986 in Stockholm by Olaf Palme
        - Reports (4 items) (Box C2., Folder 67.2.4)
          - Summary Report of Scandinavian Tour [duplicate], 1962
          - The APG's visit to Sweden, 1972 December 28
          - Establishment of a Nordic Information Pool for the Liberation Movements of Southern Africa (Uppsala), 1980 January 15
          - Statement on South Africa and Namibia at the Meeting of Nordic Foreign Ministers in Turku, 1990 March 6 - 7
        - Publications and Booklets (2 items) (Box C2., Folder 67.2.5)
          - The Dag Hammarskjöld Foundation
          - To Sweden from ANC: Commemoration of the life of Olaf Palme
    - Syria (Box C2., Folder 68)
      - Oliver Tambo Correspondence (1 item), 1984 (Box C2., Folder 68.1)
        Correspondent Syrian Communist Party. Subject Founding (60th Anniversary) and work of the Syrian Communist Party.
    - Tanzania (Box C2., Folder 69)
      - Oliver Tambo Correspondence (13 items), 1962-1989 (Box C2., Folder 69.1)
        Correspondents include National Executive Committee of Cham Cha Mapinduzi; Ali Hassan Mwinyi; Julius K. Nyere; Salim Ahmed Salim. Subjects include Messages of condolence on the death of Edward M. Sokoine (Prime Minister); 7th Summit Meeting of the PTA Authority, Arusha - 1988; Message of condolences received on the death of Johnny Makatini; Release of Nelson Mandela.
      - General (Box C2., Folder 69.2)
        - Correspondence (5 items), 1986, 1988-1989 (Box C2., Folder 69.2.1)
          Subjects include relations between the Tanzania n Government Representative, Ndugu Obezi and the ANC Administration in Mazimbu, 1986 July 9.
        - Press Release--Taganyika, Independence, 1961 March 31 (Box C2., Folder 69.2.2)
        - Publications (Box C2., Folder 69.2.3)
          - Tanzanian Policy on Foreign Affairs, Address by Mwalimu Julius K. Nyere, Tanganyika African National Union National Conference, 1967 October 16
          - President Nyerere's Speeches during his state visits to Mauritius, New Zealand, Australia and China, 1974 March 11 - 30
    - Trinidad and Tobago (Box C2., Folder 70)
      - Oliver Tambo Correspondence (3 items), 1990 (Box C2., Folder 70.1)
        Correspondents include Michael J. Williams (President of the Senate). Subjects include Release of Nelson Mandela and unbanning of ANC.
      - General (Box C2., Folder 70.2)
        - Reports (Box C2., Folder 70.2.1)
          - "Struggle for Justice: A Report on Human Rights in Trinidad and Tobago" compiled by The Trinidad and Tobago Bureau on Human Rights to commemorate World Human Rights Day, 1986 December 10
    - Tunisia (Box C2., Folder 71)
      - Oliver Tambo Correspondence (5 items), 1987-1989 (Box C2., Folder 71.1)
        Correspondents include Taieb Sahbani. Subjects include Official visit to Tunisia; Election of Zine Al-Abidine Ben Ali to the Presidency.
      - General (1 item), 1989 (Box C2., Folder 71.2)
    - Uganda (Box C2., Folder 71a)
      - General (Box C2., Folder 71a.1)
        - Correspondence (1 item), 1989 (Box C2., Folder 71a.1.1)
          Correspondence between Anthony Mongalo on behalf of Oliver Tambo and Amama Mbabazi re travel documents for ANC cadres.
      - Publication and Pamphlet (2 items), 1959-1960 (Box C2., Folder 71a.2)
        - "Uganda Political Survey," Uganda National Congress Appeal to 2nd Independent African States Conference at Addis Ababa, 1959 May - 1960 May
        - Memorandum on Uganda's Self-Determination - Presented by Uganda National Congress to 2nd Independent African States Conference, Addis Ababa, 1960 June
    - Union of Soviet Socialist Republics (Box C2., Folder 72)
      - Oliver Tambo Correspondence (1 item), 1985 (Box C2., Folder 72.1)
        Subject Soviet Instructors attached to ANC camps in Angola (See also ANC External Missions: Angola).
      - General (Box C2., Folder 72.2)
        - Speeches (Box C2., Folder 72.2.1)
          - "Triumph of Lenin’s National Policy," D. Kunaev (First Secretary, Central Committee, Communist Party of Kazakhstan), 1970 April 1
          - "New Soviet Peace Initiatives," M. Gorbachev speaks at the United Nations, ( USSR Embassy Press Release), 1988 December 7
        - Press Releases (Embassy of the USSR) (11 items), 1968, 1971, 1983, 1986, 1988, 1990 (Box C2., Folder 72.2.2)
        - Papers and Discussion Documents (27 items, various topics), uundated, 1978 (Box C2., Folder 72.2.3)
        - Organisations (Box C2., Folder 72.2.4)
          - Soviet Peace Committee, "On the Situation in Southern Africa,", 1978
          - Soviet Afro-Asian Solidarity Committee, Appeals/Statements, 1989-1990
        - Miscellaneous Report--"Economic Development" (Box C2., Folder 72.2.5)
        - Publications (Box C2., Folder 72.2.6)
          - Novosti Press Agency, News and Views, 1978 June, 1988 - 1990 August
        - Press Releases, Novosti Press Agency, 1988-1989 (Box C2., Folder 72.2.7)
        - Publications, Miscellaneous (4 items), 1978, 1980, 1986 (Box C2., Folder 72.2.8)
    - United Arab Emirates (Box C2., Folder 73)
      - Oliver Tambo Correspondence (2 items), 1975 (Box C2., Folder 73.1)
        Ahmed Khalifa Al-Suweidi (Minister of Foreign Affairs) re Symposium on Arab-African relations and co-operation.
    - United Kingdom (Box C2., Folder 74)
      - Oliver Tambo Correspondence (22 items), 1986-1991 (Box C2., Folder 74.1)
        Correspondents include Lord Barber; Bernie Grant; Haringey Council; Lord John Hatch; Geoffrey Howe; Neil Kinnock; National Union of Mineworkers; Steven Miles; Sir David Steele; W. K. K. White (High Commissioner). Subjects include British Government/European Community's stance on Apartheid.
        - Programme--Service of Thanksgiving for the life and work of Geoffrey H. C. Bing, Addressed to Oliver and Adelaide Tambo
      - General (Box C2, Folder 74.2)
        - Correspondence (9 items), 1983, 1986-1988 (Box C2., Folder 74.2.1)
          Correspondents include Geoffrey Howe; Nathaniel Masemola; Margaret Thatcher; Dennis Worral.
        - Speeches (7 items), 1978, 1986-1990 (Box C2., Folder 74.2.2)
          - Text of Dr. Owen's Speech to the General Assembly of the United Nations, 1978 September 27
          - " South Africa: No Easy Answers"
          - Interviews (extracts)-- Margaret Thatcher
          - Extract from a speech by William Waldegrave, " South Africa - Realism is Winning Through"
        - Miscellaneous (Box C2., Folder 74.2.3)
          - Greater London Council's Anti-Apartheid Declaration
        - Reports
          - "British Policy Towards South Africa"
          - "House of Lords Official Report" (item on South Africa and Sanctions), 1991
          - House of Commons Foreign Affairs Committee - Session 1984-85, The Situation in South Africa/Minutes of Evidence ( ANC - Oliver Tambo; Thabo Mbeki; A. Pahad)
    - United States of America (Box C2., Folder 75)
      - Oliver Tambo Correspondence (23 items), 1980-1990 (Box C2., Folder 75.1)
        Correspondents include Barbara Harmel; Rev. Jesse Jackson; Edward Kennedy; Paul E. Tsongas. Subjects include Report by Paul E. Tsongas on visit to seven African states; sanctions debate; visit to the US; Tribute to Oliver Tambo by Senator Edward Kennedy, 1990.
      - General (4 items), 1985-1986, 1989 (Box C2., Folder 75.2)
        - Correspondence re Project South Africa Invitation/Programme (Box C2., Folder 75.2.1)
        - Reports (8 items) (Box C2., Folder 75.2.2)
          - Apartheid as an oppressive and violent system and the ANC as a movement dedicated to change and democracy in South Africa
          - Report of a meeting between the ANC and Robert Cabelly, special assistant to Chester Crocker, US Information Office, Lusaka, 1983 September 7
          - Rebuttals to criticism of ANC President Oliver Tambo's meeting with Secretary Shultz
          - ANC meeting with William Roberts
          - Memorandum, Talking points for Hani Meeting with Jeffrey Davidow, 1991 April 22
          - The United States, Africa and the International Division of Labour
        - Speeches, Statements and Interviews (14 items) (Box C2., Folder 75.2.4)
          - South Africa: Strategy for Change, Chester Crocker, 1980-1981
          - Interview with Chester Crocker, Howard Scripps, 1981
          - Statement from the Office of Senator Edward M. Kennedy re visit to South Africa, 1985
        - Press Releases, US Information Service, undated, 1976-1981, 1986 (Box C2., Folder 72.2.5)
    - Uruguay (Box C2., Folder 76)
      - General (Box C2., Folder 76.1)
        - Uruguay and South African Apartheid, Uruguayan Association against Racism and Apartheid, 1983
    - Venezuela (Box C2., Folder 77)
      - Oliver Tambo Correspondence (5 items), 1988-1989 (Box C2., Folder 77.1)
        Includes correspondence with Carlos Andres Perez. Subjects include Honourary Doctorate to be conferred on Nelson Mandela; electoral victory for Carlos Andres Perez, 1989.
    - Vietnam (Box C2., Folder 78)
      - Correspondence (2 items), 1968-1969 (Box C2., Folder 78.1)
        Subjects support of the people of Vietnam; message of condolences over the death of President Ho Chi Minh.
      - Speech given by Nguyen Ho, member of the Standing Committee of the City Communist Party, President of Ho Chi Minh City Committee of Solidarity and friendship with world peoples at reception in honour of ANC delegation, 1978 October 17
      - Statement by Nguyen Van Linh, General Secretary of the Communist Party of Vietnam at the Meeting of Parties and Organisations, Moscow, 1987 Septmber 4 - 5
    - Yugoslavia (Box C2., Folder 79)
      - Oliver Tambo Correspondence (10 items), 1971, 1977-1978, 1989 (Box C2., Folder 79.1)
        Correspondents include Ambassadors of Yugoslavia.
      - General (Box C2., Folder 79.2)
        - Correspondence (2 items)
    - Zaire
      - Oliver Tambo Correspondence (3 items), undated, 1972, 1988 (Box C2., Folder 80.1)
        Correspondents include Political exile - Nkamba-Ilunga wa Mwenga (Ligue des Sans-Partie); Bande Larity Nyarende (Ambassador). Subjects include 20th Anniversary of the Independence of Zaire.
      - General (Box C2., Folder 80.2)
        - List/Notes - Miscellaneous
        - Statement,"The Cartel's position towards People's aspirations for fundamental change in Congo 'Zaire',", 1990 April 15
    - Zambia, undated, 1962, 1984-1989 (Box C2., Folder 81)
      - Oliver Tambo Correspondence (Box C2., Folder 81.1)
        Correspondents include Kenneth Kaunda; E. H. K. Mudenda. Subjects include 20th Anniversary of the Independence of Zambia/26th Anniversary of UNIP/60th Birthday of Kenneth Kaunda; message of condolences on the death of Nalumino Mundia; 24th Anniversary of the Independence of Zambia; Namibian Elections.
      - General (Box C2., Folder 81.2)
        - Correspondence (Box C2., Folder 81.2.1)
          - 1967-1973 (42 items) (Box C2., Folder 81.2.1.1)
          - 1975-1976, 1988-1989 (42 items) (Box C2., Folder 81.2.1.2)
        - Statements and Speeches (Box C2., Folder 81.2.2)
          - ANC Statements (4 items), undated, 1962, 1987-1988 (Box C2., Folder 81.2.2.1)
            - Statement on the Question of Negotiations, 1987 October 9
            - Statement addressed to the 10th General Conference, UNIP, Kabwe, Zambia, 1988 August 18 - 23
          - Kenneth Kaunda (6 items), 1969, 1975, 1978, 1982, 1987, 1989 (Box C2., Folder 81.2.2.2)
            - Address to the UNIP National Council, Matero, Lusaka, 1969 August 11
            - Africa's Constant Plea - remarks made at a White House dinner given in his honour by President Gerald R. Ford, 1975 April 19
            - Speech, officially opening the World Council of Churches' Meeting, Pamodzi Hotel, 1987 May 4
          - Remarks on the Presentation of the Main Gift on 64th Birthday of His Excellency, Dr. K. Kaunda at State House, 1988 April 28 (Box C2., Folder 81.2.2.3)
          - Miscellaneous Statement (Box C2., Folder 81.2.2.4)
            - The Lusaka Statement - representations of churches, trade unions, Women's Youth (sic) and anti-apartheid groups from South Africa, Namibia and other parts of the world, Lusaka, 1987 May 4 - 8
        - Miscellaneous (Box C2., Folder 81.2.3)
          - Reports; The National Anthem; Applications for a Zambia Travel Document; programme for the official visit by the Prime Minister of New Zealand, 1985
    - Zimbabwe (Box C2., Folder 82.2)
      - Oliver Tambo Correspondence (16 items), 1971-1989 (Box C2., Folder 82.1)
        Correspondents include M. Mangwende; E. D. Mnangagwa; D. N. E. Mutasa; N. M. Shamuyarira; James Chikerema; Robert Mugabe. Subjects include Non-Aligned Movement Summit Conference (1986, 1989); elections of the First President under the Constitution of Zimbabwe Amendment (1987); Unity accord between ZANU (PF) and PF-ZAPU (1987); message of condolences on Johnny Makatini’s death; Campaign of Mrs. McBride on the death sentence imposed on Robert McBride; Conference of Socialist International and Frontline States on Southern Africa; message of condolences Maurice Nyagumbo’s death.
      - General (Box C2., Folder 82.2)
        - Zimbabwe African National Union ( ZANU) (Box C2., Folder 82.2.1)
          - Correspondence (2 items) (Box C2., Folder 82.2.1.1)
          - Report--The Party’s Ideological Concept (Box C2., Folder 82.2.1.2)
          - Statements and Communiqués (5 items), undated, 1970, 1977 (Box C2., Folder 82.2.1.3)
            - Statement addressed to the ANC on the occasion of its 60th Birthday
            - Death in detention of the Vice President of ZANU, Leopald Takawira
          - Miscellaneous--Sticker, Rhodesia is Zimbabwe - Support ZANU for action inside Zimbabwe Now (Box C2., Folder 82.2.1.4)
        - Zimbabwe African People’s Union ( ZAPU) (Box C2., Folder 82.2.2)
          - Correspondence re formal expulsion of James Chikerema, George Nyaudoro and Stephen Pariernyatwa (Former members of ZAPU) (Box C2., Folder 82.2.2.1)
          - Reports (Box C2., Folder 82.2.2.2)
            - "'Amagolilia' - that's what they call guerrilla's"
            - Facts about ZAPU and ZANU ( ZAPU)
            - Communiqué ZAPU and ANC
            - Crimes of the Rhodesian Colonial Regime against the People of Zimbabwe and Independent African States, presented by ZAPU before the International Commission of Inquiry into the Crimes of the Racist and Apartheid Regimes in Southern Africa, Brussels, 1979 February 9 - 12
            - Summary - Session with Minister of Education re placement of ANC students in Zimbabwe, 1984
          - Publications (Box C2., Folder 82.2.2.3)
            - The Zimbabwe People's Voice, Official Organ of ZAPU, Vol. 1 No.73, 1978 November
          - Miscellaneous (Box C2., Folder 82.2.2.4)
            - The Inaugural Africa Prize for Leadership Address - Robert Mugabe, The Hunger Project, 1988
          - Press Cuttings, Zimbabwe Fact Sheet (Box C2., Folder 82.2.2.5)
  - Individuals (Box C3)
    - Lewis John Collins (Box C3., Folder 1)
      - Programme of Funeral, St Paul's Cathedral, 1983 January 11
    - King Sabata Dalindyebo, Medical Report, 1986 April 14 (Box C3., Folder 2)
    - Ruth First-- Ronald Segal's tribute to Ruth First, Hampstead Town Hall (Box C3., Folder 4)
    - Chris Hani’s Assassination (Box C3., Folder 5)
      - Correspondence between Angela E. V. King (UN Observer Mission in South Africa) and Nelson Mandela, 1993 April 10
      - Press Releases,Statements (5 items)
    - Archbishop Trevor Huddleston (Box C3., Folder 6)
      - Correspondence (3 items), 1984, 1986, 1990
        Correspondents include C. D. Powell; Margaret Thatcher.
      - Statement and Speech (2 items)
        - Statement by Rev. T. Huddleston, President, Anti-Apartheid Movement, on launching the Anti-Apartheid Movement's Ten-Point Programme of Action
        - Canon Collins Memorial Lecture: South Africa at the Crossroads, 1986
    - A. Kathrada Speech and Statement (2 items) (Box C3., Folder 7)
    - David and Norma Kitson (Box C3., Folder 8)
      - Correspondence (Box C3., Folder 8.1)
        - 1982-1984 (18 items) (Box C3., Folder 8.1.1)
        - 1985-1987, 1990 (17 items) (Box C3., Folder 8.1.2)
      - Kitson Committee (Box C3., Folder 8.2)
        - Minutes (3 items), 1981-1983
        - Booklet, One Union's Fight against Apartheid - The Story of the Free Dave Kitson Campaign
        - Circular Leaflet
      - Justice for Kitson Campaign (Box C3., Folder 8.3)
        - Circular Letter/Pamphlet (2 items), 1989
      - Anti-Apartheid Movement/Group (Box C3., Folder 8.4)
        - Minutes, City Branch (4 items), 1982 February - April
        - Pamphlets, Circular Letters, Press Releases re activities including pickets outside South Africa House (See Photographs; 8 items)
        - Membership Card, Adelaide Tambo (Founder)
      - Photographs (9 items) (Box C3., Folder 8.5)